<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Entertainment &#8211; Latest News Today</title>
	<atom:link href="http:///www.latestnewstoday.com.ng/category/entertainment/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http:///www.latestnewstoday.com.ng</link>
	<description>Breaking news, latest news, politics, entertainment, business, technology, lifestyle, sports, headlines and happenings in Nigeria and the world at large.</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 08:29:40 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.0</generator>

<image>
	<url>http:///www.latestnewstoday.com.ng/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/latestnewtoday-removebg-preview.png</url>
	<title>Entertainment &#8211; Latest News Today</title>
	<link>http:///www.latestnewstoday.com.ng</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Terror-linked Minister, Pantami Orders Government Ministries, Agencies To Stop Using Gmail, Yahoo Mail For Official Communication</title>
		<link>http:///www.latestnewstoday.com.ng/terror-linked-minister-pantami-orders-government-ministries-agencies-to-stop-using-gmail-yahoo-mail-for-official-communication/</link>
					<comments>http:///www.latestnewstoday.com.ng/terror-linked-minister-pantami-orders-government-ministries-agencies-to-stop-using-gmail-yahoo-mail-for-official-communication/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[webconnector]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 08:29:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Entertainment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Latest News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lifestyle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http:///www.latestnewstoday.com.ng/?p=36</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Isa Pantami, the Minister of Communications and Digital Economy, has said the federal government has outlawed the use of generic internet domains for official purposes. Pantami said this on Wednesday while addressing newsmen at the end of the weekly federal executive council (FEC) meeting presided over by Vice-President, Yemi Osinbajo. The minister, controversial for his [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http:///www.latestnewstoday.com.ng/terror-linked-minister-pantami-orders-government-ministries-agencies-to-stop-using-gmail-yahoo-mail-for-official-communication/">Terror-linked Minister, Pantami Orders Government Ministries, Agencies To Stop Using Gmail, Yahoo Mail For Official Communication</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http:///www.latestnewstoday.com.ng">Latest News Today</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p>
<div>
<p>Isa Pantami, the Minister of Communications and Digital Economy, has said the federal government has outlawed the use of generic internet domains for official purposes.</p>
<p><span class="container container-pod container-pod-short"><span class="adunit-parent hide block-module block-module-ad block-module-ad-300x250"><span class="block-module-image-wrapper"><span class="block-module-image adunit hide" data-adunit="story-300x250-mobile-billboard" data-adsize="300,250" data-adscreenmax="767"></span></span></span></span></p>
<p>Pantami said this on Wednesday while addressing newsmen at the end of the weekly federal executive council (FEC) meeting presided over by Vice-President, Yemi Osinbajo.</p>
<p>
<span class="ds-1col file file-image file-image-jpeg view-mode-embedded  centered clearfix block-story-object block-story-object-resource block-story-object-resource-image"><br />
<span class="block-story-object-asset"><img class="media-element file-embedded" typeof="foaf:Image" src="https://saharareporters.com/sites/default/files/styles/normal_medium/public/Isa-Ali-Pantami2.jpeg?itok=5hrogwIw" alt="" /></span><span class="block-story-object-content"></span><br />
</span>
</p>
<p>The minister, controversial for his extremist terrorists preaching, said the council approved the “National Policy on the Government, Second Level Domain”, which mandates the migration of all official communications from generic domains to the nation’s second-level domain under the government top-level domain.</p>
<p>Pantami, whose removal had been demanded by a lot of Nigerians over terrorism-related comments, explained that all government agencies must switch to an official communication medium and stop using public email systems such as Gmail, Yahoo mail, Hotmail, and others.</p>
<p>“This policy has been approved, and it focuses more on mandating federal public institutions, ministries, departments, agencies (MDAs) and all institutions as long as they are for government; they should migrate from using generic domains in their websites and their emails to our second level domain under government top-level domain,” Pantami said.</p>
<p>“For example, you will discover today, some government institutions will engage in official communications using private email: yahoo.com, hotmail.com, gmail.com.</p>
<p>“And it is an official communication and someone may retire or will complete his tenure or the tenure can be terminated, and he will go with the same email. And in that email, there are many official documents.</p>
<p>“So, this will not be tolerated by the government anymore. Any official communications must be using an official email and that email should not be a generic one, it must be ‘.gov.ng.’ What is most important is ‘.ng’ that is our national identity.”</p>
<p>“There are many categories of the second-level domain, some are for military, you will see like mil.ng mil is a short form of military.ng for Nigeria. You can see .gov.ng — Gov for government and ng for Nigeria.</p>
<p>“So, there are categories of the second-level domain, while our country top-level domain.ng must be there in our websites so that whoever gets access will know that this website is from Nigeria, while for email, it must reflect the official name.”</p>
<p> </p>
</div>
<p><a href="https://saharareporters.com/2022/02/17/terror-linked-minister-pantami-orders-government-ministries-agencies-stop-using-gmail">Source link </a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http:///www.latestnewstoday.com.ng/terror-linked-minister-pantami-orders-government-ministries-agencies-to-stop-using-gmail-yahoo-mail-for-official-communication/">Terror-linked Minister, Pantami Orders Government Ministries, Agencies To Stop Using Gmail, Yahoo Mail For Official Communication</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http:///www.latestnewstoday.com.ng">Latest News Today</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>http:///www.latestnewstoday.com.ng/terror-linked-minister-pantami-orders-government-ministries-agencies-to-stop-using-gmail-yahoo-mail-for-official-communication/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>I Rejected Use Of Mobile Phones For Over One Year When It Was Introduced To Nigeria – Buhari’s Communications Minister, Pantami</title>
		<link>http:///www.latestnewstoday.com.ng/i-rejected-use-of-mobile-phones-for-over-one-year-when-it-was-introduced-to-nigeria-buharis-communications-minister-pantami/</link>
					<comments>http:///www.latestnewstoday.com.ng/i-rejected-use-of-mobile-phones-for-over-one-year-when-it-was-introduced-to-nigeria-buharis-communications-minister-pantami/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[webconnector]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 03:54:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Entertainment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Latest News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lifestyle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http:///www.latestnewstoday.com.ng/?p=30</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Nigeria’s Minister of Communication and Digital Economy, Isa Pantami, says Nigerians have the right to be sceptical about the deployment of the 5G Network in the country due to certain beliefs they hold. Pantami, who is the Chairman of the National Frequency Management Council, said he was one of those who kicked against the use of [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http:///www.latestnewstoday.com.ng/i-rejected-use-of-mobile-phones-for-over-one-year-when-it-was-introduced-to-nigeria-buharis-communications-minister-pantami/">I Rejected Use Of Mobile Phones For Over One Year When It Was Introduced To Nigeria – Buhari’s Communications Minister, Pantami</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http:///www.latestnewstoday.com.ng">Latest News Today</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p>
<div>
<p>Nigeria’s Minister of Communication and Digital Economy, Isa Pantami, says Nigerians have the right to be sceptical about the deployment of the 5G Network in the country due to certain beliefs they hold.<br /> <br />Pantami, who is the Chairman of the National Frequency Management Council, said he was one of those who kicked against the use of mobile phones when it was first introduced in the country.</p>
<p><span class="container container-pod container-pod-short"><span class="adunit-parent hide block-module block-module-ad block-module-ad-300x250"><span class="block-module-image-wrapper"><span class="block-module-image adunit hide" data-adunit="story-300x250-mobile-billboard" data-adsize="300,250" data-adscreenmax="767"></span></span></span></span></p>
<p>
<span class="ds-1col file file-image file-image-jpeg view-mode-embedded  centered clearfix block-story-object block-story-object-resource block-story-object-resource-image"><br />
<span class="block-story-object-asset"><img class="media-element file-embedded" typeof="foaf:Image" src="https://saharareporters.com/sites/default/files/styles/normal_medium/public/Isa-Ali-Pantami-Isa-Pantami-Isa-Ali-Ibrahim-Pantami.jpeg?itok=W5hVhHKX" alt="" /></span><span class="block-story-object-content"></span><br />
</span>
</p>
<p>He made the disclosure as a way to allay the negative speculations on the deployment of the 5G network in the country.<br /> <br />Pantami spoke at the public presentation of National Policy on 5G Network and Spectrum for 5G Deployment and the hand-over of the 3.5 gigahertz spectrum to the Nigerian Communications Commission in Abuja.<br /> <br />He said he was against the use of mobile phones because of negative beliefs he held at the time.<br /> <br />However, he attributed some of the theories about 5G in Nigeria to false information circulated by people with no substantial evidence to show for their rejection.<br /> <br />The Minister said, “In 2020 if I could recall vividly in April and May, it was something else. Many citizens were complaining that 5G brought about COVID-19. You know how crazy we are in this country. Anything you drop without looking at the source or authenticity, people will take it.<br /> <br />“I can personally recall that when mobile phones came into Nigeria, some people resisted and there was an allegation that it was linked to cancer and many more.<br /> <br />“I will not feel shy to say that even my humble self, I couldn’t accept the use of mobile phones till after one year. A friend of mine who was working here in Abuja then purchased the mobile phone, and SIM card and sent it to me and said I must use it.<br /> <br />“Maybe he wanted to keep in touch with me so he compelled me to accept mobile phones then. This is to show you that that is our nature. Sometimes we tend to be conservative in doing that.”<br /> <br />On the 5G, he stated that the government suspended the deployment of the technology to address the concerns of Nigerians which was important to the Muhammadu Buhari administration.<br /> <br />He said, “If one person is to be infected by COVID-19 virus, then I should be number one in Nigeria.<br /> <br />“Yesterday I did another Covid test prior to the Federal Executive Council, it was my 52nd test and I’m grateful to almighty Allah that all of them are negative.”<br /> <br />Nigerians have described Pantami, an Islamic cleric, as a closet extremist after the Islamist views he held in the past came to light in 2021.<br /> <br />The Buhari government, however, said it would stand by the minister.<br /> <br />Pantami expressed views sympathetic to groups such as al-Qaeda and Boko Haram.<br /> <br />In a sermon from the 2000s, he said he considered al-Qaeda founder, Osama Bin Laden, a better Muslim than himself. For instance, in a 2006 speech, he publicly offered his condolences after the death of al-Qaeda&#8217;s leader in Iraq, Abu Musab al-Zarqawi.<br /> <br />In another, he said he was happy when infidels were massacred.</p>
</div>
<p><a href="https://saharareporters.com/2022/02/18/i-rejected-use-mobile-phones-over-one-year-when-it-was-introduced-nigeria-%E2%80%93-buhari%E2%80%99s">Source link </a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http:///www.latestnewstoday.com.ng/i-rejected-use-of-mobile-phones-for-over-one-year-when-it-was-introduced-to-nigeria-buharis-communications-minister-pantami/">I Rejected Use Of Mobile Phones For Over One Year When It Was Introduced To Nigeria – Buhari’s Communications Minister, Pantami</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http:///www.latestnewstoday.com.ng">Latest News Today</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>http:///www.latestnewstoday.com.ng/i-rejected-use-of-mobile-phones-for-over-one-year-when-it-was-introduced-to-nigeria-buharis-communications-minister-pantami/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>We’re Expecting Twitter To Open Nigerian Office By March 2022 — Buhari Government</title>
		<link>http:///www.latestnewstoday.com.ng/were-expecting-twitter-to-open-nigerian-office-by-march-2022-buhari-government/</link>
					<comments>http:///www.latestnewstoday.com.ng/were-expecting-twitter-to-open-nigerian-office-by-march-2022-buhari-government/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[webconnector]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 03:36:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Entertainment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Latest News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lifestyle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http:///www.latestnewstoday.com.ng/?p=18</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The Muhammadu Buhari-led federal government has said that microblogging site, Twitter, is expected to open its Nigerian office before the end of March 2022. The Minister of Information and Culture, Lai Mohammed, made this known when he appeared on a radio progarmme, the Radio Link, in Abuja, noting that the move was part of the [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http:///www.latestnewstoday.com.ng/were-expecting-twitter-to-open-nigerian-office-by-march-2022-buhari-government/">We’re Expecting Twitter To Open Nigerian Office By March 2022 — Buhari Government</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http:///www.latestnewstoday.com.ng">Latest News Today</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p>
<div>
<p>The Muhammadu Buhari-led federal government has said that microblogging site, Twitter, is expected to open its Nigerian office before the end of March 2022.</p>
<p><span class="container container-pod container-pod-short"><span class="adunit-parent hide block-module block-module-ad block-module-ad-300x250"><span class="block-module-image-wrapper"><span class="block-module-image adunit hide" data-adunit="story-300x250-mobile-billboard" data-adsize="300,250" data-adscreenmax="767"></span></span></span></span></p>
<p>The Minister of Information and Culture, Lai Mohammed, made this known when he appeared on a radio progarmme, the Radio Link, in Abuja, noting that the move was part of the agreement the company reached with the Federal Government last year to have the ban imposed on it lifted.</p>
<p>
<span class="ds-1col file file-image file-image-jpeg view-mode-embedded  centered clearfix block-story-object block-story-object-resource block-story-object-resource-image"><br />
<span class="block-story-object-asset"><img class="media-element file-embedded" typeof="foaf:Image" src="https://saharareporters.com/sites/default/files/styles/normal_medium/public/S107672684_preview.jpg?itok=OOG4IRHe" alt="" /></span><span class="block-story-object-content"></span><br />
</span>
</p>
<p>Mohammed asserted that other social media platforms operating in the country would be expected to follow suit, adding that in due course, as the government vowed to ensure that only wholesome content was allowed to pass through the platforms henceforth.</p>
<p>He stressed that the government’s intention to regulate social media was borne out of the desire to sanitise social media and not to stifle the freedom of speech and expression or strangulate the media as some people might believe.</p>
<p>He said, “Twitter also agreed to comply with all payable taxes, as they are operating under Nigerian laws and this they agreed to do within one week of restoring their operations.</p>
<p>”Twitter agreed to immediately work with the Federal Government in the area of code of conduct, that was in line with global best practices</p>
<p>“Twitter agreed to immediately enroll Nigerians in its law enforcement portals and Partners Support Portal.</p>
<p>“The law enforcement portal will provide dedicated channels for the Nigerian law enforcement agencies to escalate reports on contents that violate the code of conduct or national laws.</p>
<p>“Similarly, the partner support portal provides a direct channel for government to engage Twitter staff to manage prohibited contents.</p>
<p>“We are going to regulate the social media not because we want to stifle the media or we want to violate the right of expression. We want to ensure that only wholesome contents are available on social media.</p>
<p>“Recently, we were all shocked when an 18-year old boy, accused of killing his 21-year old girlfriend for money rituals, confessed that he learnt the diabolical act on social media. The teenager, in collaboration with his friends, cut off the head of the victim and was burning it in a pot when they were apprehended.”</p>
<p>“The government has the responsibility to ensure that social media platforms were responsible and the contents they displayed are not harmful to young people, as well as the unity of the country,” he said.</p>
<p>The minister affirmed that relevant laws and the broadcasting code would be amended to ensure that the agreement reached with Twitter was applicable to other social media platforms.</p>
</div>
<p><a href="https://saharareporters.com/2022/02/22/we%E2%80%99re-expecting-twitter-open-nigerian-office-march-2022-%E2%80%94-buhari-government">Source link </a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http:///www.latestnewstoday.com.ng/were-expecting-twitter-to-open-nigerian-office-by-march-2022-buhari-government/">We’re Expecting Twitter To Open Nigerian Office By March 2022 — Buhari Government</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http:///www.latestnewstoday.com.ng">Latest News Today</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>http:///www.latestnewstoday.com.ng/were-expecting-twitter-to-open-nigerian-office-by-march-2022-buhari-government/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>35million Nigerians Not Yet Connected To Telecommunications, Digital Financial Services</title>
		<link>http:///www.latestnewstoday.com.ng/35million-nigerians-not-yet-connected-to-telecommunications-digital-financial-services/</link>
					<comments>http:///www.latestnewstoday.com.ng/35million-nigerians-not-yet-connected-to-telecommunications-digital-financial-services/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[webconnector]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 03:33:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Entertainment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Latest News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lifestyle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http:///www.latestnewstoday.com.ng/?p=16</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>At least 35million Nigerians do not yet have access to telecommunications and digital financial services. This was made known on Tuesday by the executive vice-chairman of the Nigerian Communications Commission (NCC), Umar Danbatta, in Abuja during an event to commemorate World Consumer Rights Day 2022, with the theme “Fair Digital Finance.” The NCC boss emphasised [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http:///www.latestnewstoday.com.ng/35million-nigerians-not-yet-connected-to-telecommunications-digital-financial-services/">35million Nigerians Not Yet Connected To Telecommunications, Digital Financial Services</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http:///www.latestnewstoday.com.ng">Latest News Today</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p>
<div>
<p>At least 35million Nigerians do not yet have access to telecommunications and digital financial services.</p>
<p><span class="container container-pod container-pod-short"><span class="adunit-parent hide block-module block-module-ad block-module-ad-300x250"><span class="block-module-image-wrapper"><span class="block-module-image adunit hide" data-adunit="story-300x250-mobile-billboard" data-adsize="300,250" data-adscreenmax="767"></span></span></span></span></p>
<p>This was made known on Tuesday by the executive vice-chairman of the Nigerian Communications Commission (NCC), Umar Danbatta, in Abuja during an event to commemorate World Consumer Rights Day 2022, with the theme “Fair Digital Finance.”</p>
<p>
<span class="ds-1col file file-image file-image-jpeg view-mode-embedded  centered clearfix block-story-object block-story-object-resource block-story-object-resource-image"><br />
<span class="block-story-object-asset"><img class="media-element file-embedded" typeof="foaf:Image" src="https://saharareporters.com/sites/default/files/styles/normal_medium/public/Internet-Service-Providers-ISPs-e1555404914471.jpg?itok=QqVgLPn-" alt="" /></span><span class="block-story-object-content"></span><br />
</span>
</p>
<p>The NCC boss emphasised the need for increased investments in fixed and wireless infrastructure to boost financial inclusion.</p>
<p>“As many as 35 million Nigerians are yet to have access to telecommunications services, and by implication, they lack access to digital financial services,” Danbatta said.</p>
<p>“This situation denies these Nigerians access to digital financial inclusion. It is a challenge that is attributable to the inadequacy of both wireless and fibre connectivity infrastructure.</p>
<p>“The fact remains that more citizens will embrace the digital financial culture when they have access to telecom services in the distant, isolated, unserved and underserved communities where they dwell.”</p>
<p>“We are therefore conscious of the urgency of increasing investment in both fixed and wireless infrastructure,” Danbatta said.</p>
<p>“This will make the target of at least 80 percent level of financial inclusion in about four years possible.</p>
<p>“The commission has thus licensed the infrastructure companies (Infracos), which are to provide the fibre from landing ports to the hinterland of the country. A key focus in this regard is to provide broadband connectivity, especially in the 774 local government areas in the country.</p>
<p>“There would be further actions to enable Infracos to commence operations as the commission recognises that fibre is the long-term solution to the volume of transactions in the financial services sector.”</p>
<p>Danbatta who called on stakeholders in the digital finance sector to protect consumers from financial losses, disclosed that the commission would soon establish telecom consumer assistance, resolution and enquiries (TELCARE) desks at strategic locations across the country to provide information to telecom consumers.</p>
</div>
<p><a href="https://saharareporters.com/2022/03/16/35million-nigerians-not-yet-connected-telecommunications-digital-financial-services">Source link </a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http:///www.latestnewstoday.com.ng/35million-nigerians-not-yet-connected-to-telecommunications-digital-financial-services/">35million Nigerians Not Yet Connected To Telecommunications, Digital Financial Services</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http:///www.latestnewstoday.com.ng">Latest News Today</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>http:///www.latestnewstoday.com.ng/35million-nigerians-not-yet-connected-to-telecommunications-digital-financial-services/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Abuja, Kogi, Anambra, Six Other States May Experience Communications Blackout — Telecoms Operators Warn</title>
		<link>http:///www.latestnewstoday.com.ng/abuja-kogi-anambra-six-other-states-may-experience-communications-blackout-telecoms-operators-warn/</link>
					<comments>http:///www.latestnewstoday.com.ng/abuja-kogi-anambra-six-other-states-may-experience-communications-blackout-telecoms-operators-warn/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[webconnector]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 03:27:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Entertainment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Latest News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lifestyle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http:///www.latestnewstoday.com.ng/?p=14</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Kogi State, the Federal Capital Territory and seven other states in the country may experience a telecom blackout from Tuesday if President Muhammadu Buhari does not prevail on the Kogi State Government to unseal certain telecom infrastructures locked down in the state, telecommunications operators have warned. The Kogi State government, according to the telcos, had [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http:///www.latestnewstoday.com.ng/abuja-kogi-anambra-six-other-states-may-experience-communications-blackout-telecoms-operators-warn/">Abuja, Kogi, Anambra, Six Other States May Experience Communications Blackout — Telecoms Operators Warn</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http:///www.latestnewstoday.com.ng">Latest News Today</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p>
<div>
<p>Kogi State, the Federal Capital Territory and seven other states in the country may experience a telecom blackout from Tuesday if President Muhammadu Buhari does not prevail on the Kogi State Government to unseal certain telecom infrastructures locked down in the state, telecommunications operators have warned.</p>
<p><span class="container container-pod container-pod-short"><span class="adunit-parent hide block-module block-module-ad block-module-ad-300x250"><span class="block-module-image-wrapper"><span class="block-module-image adunit hide" data-adunit="story-300x250-mobile-billboard" data-adsize="300,250" data-adscreenmax="767"></span></span></span></span></p>
<p>The Kogi State government, according to the telcos, had shut down the facilities over the alleged failure to pay some taxes and levies.</p>
<p>
<span class="ds-1col file file-image file-image-jpeg view-mode-embedded  centered clearfix block-story-object block-story-object-resource block-story-object-resource-image"><br />
<span class="block-story-object-asset"><img class="media-element file-embedded" typeof="foaf:Image" src="https://saharareporters.com/sites/default/files/styles/normal_medium/public/Telecoms-operators.jpeg?itok=pWpR6OmT" alt="" /></span><span class="block-story-object-content"></span><br />
</span>
</p>
<p>However, the Chairman of the umbrella body of the telcos, Association of Licensed Telecom Operators of Nigeria, ALTON, Gbenga Adebayo, claimed that his members had paid all legitimate taxes and levies in the state, describing the ones in dispute as “unusual.”</p>
<p>According to him, over 70 sites within the state and environs have shut down as a result of wich their members are unable to have access and maintain them.</p>
<p>He called on President Buhari to intervene urgently to avert telecom blackout that may affect Abuja, too.</p>
<p>A statement issued by the body and signed by Adebayo, noted, “The Association of Licensed Telecommunications Operators of Nigeria, ALTON wishes to express concern about the shutting down of telecommunications facilities in Kogi State as a result of disputes arising from unusual taxes and levies demanded by the Kogi State Government through its Internal Revenue Service (KIRS).</p>
<p>“This issue is likely to lead to a total communications blackout in the entire Kogi State, parts of Abuja the Federal Capital Territory.”</p>
<p>It will also “impact on service availability in some parts of the following states: Nassarawa, Benue, Enugu, Anambra, Edo, Ondo, Ekiti, Kwara, Niger States. These are States sharing borders with Kogi State.</p>
<p>“This situation arises as a number of critical telecommunications sites belonging to our members have been closed and sealed up by Kogi State Government in an attempt to increase Internally Generated Revenue IGR collection.</p>
<p>“This action followed an ex-parte court order obtained by the KIRS over unsubstantiated allegations that our members are in default of tax payments to the state government (which is not the truth) and access to these critical telecom sites has been denied.</p>
<p>“As a result of these actions by the state government, our members are unable to refuel power generators in these sites, a situation which has led to outage of over 70 sites including hub sites across parts of Kogi State.</p>
<p>“Now, with likely impact on nine states surrounding Kogi (namely:- Nasarawa, Benue, Enugu, Anambra, Edo, Ondo, Ekiti, Kwara, Niger states. These are states sharing borders with Kogi State; and Abuja the FCT inclusive.</p>
<p>“We are very concerned that this indiscriminate action has the potential of further leading to a total telecommunications outage in Kogi State with neighbouring states and parts of the Federal Capital Territory adversely impacted.</p>
<p>“To the best of our knowledge, our members have settled all statutory levies and taxes due the Kogi State Government and have taken necessary steps to comply with local laws that govern business activities within Kogi State.”</p>
</div>
<p><a href="https://saharareporters.com/2022/03/29/abuja-kogi-anambra-six-other-states-may-experience-communications-blackout-%E2%80%94-telecoms">Source link </a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http:///www.latestnewstoday.com.ng/abuja-kogi-anambra-six-other-states-may-experience-communications-blackout-telecoms-operators-warn/">Abuja, Kogi, Anambra, Six Other States May Experience Communications Blackout — Telecoms Operators Warn</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http:///www.latestnewstoday.com.ng">Latest News Today</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>http:///www.latestnewstoday.com.ng/abuja-kogi-anambra-six-other-states-may-experience-communications-blackout-telecoms-operators-warn/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nigerian Government Directs MTN, Other Telecom Companies To Bar Calls From SIM Cards Not Linked With National Identity Number, NIN</title>
		<link>http:///www.latestnewstoday.com.ng/nigerian-government-directs-mtn-other-telecom-companies-to-bar-calls-from-sim-cards-not-linked-with-national-identity-number-nin/</link>
					<comments>http:///www.latestnewstoday.com.ng/nigerian-government-directs-mtn-other-telecom-companies-to-bar-calls-from-sim-cards-not-linked-with-national-identity-number-nin/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[webconnector]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 03:25:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Entertainment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Latest News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lifestyle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http:///www.latestnewstoday.com.ng/?p=12</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The Nigerian Government, on Monday, ordered telecommunications companies to bar outgoing calls on mobile lines not linked with the National Identification Number (NIN).   This was made known by the Minister of Communications and Digital Economy, Isa Pantami, in a statement on Monday. According to him, the move is part of the implementation of the [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http:///www.latestnewstoday.com.ng/nigerian-government-directs-mtn-other-telecom-companies-to-bar-calls-from-sim-cards-not-linked-with-national-identity-number-nin/">Nigerian Government Directs MTN, Other Telecom Companies To Bar Calls From SIM Cards Not Linked With National Identity Number, NIN</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http:///www.latestnewstoday.com.ng">Latest News Today</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p></p>
<div>
<p>The Nigerian Government, on Monday, ordered telecommunications companies to bar outgoing calls on mobile lines not linked with the National Identification Number (NIN).</p>
<p><span class="container container-pod container-pod-short"><span class="adunit-parent hide block-module block-module-ad block-module-ad-300x250"><span class="block-module-image-wrapper"><span class="block-module-image adunit hide" data-adunit="story-300x250-mobile-billboard" data-adsize="300,250" data-adscreenmax="767"></span></span></span></span></p>
<p> </p>
<p>This was made known by the Minister of Communications and Digital Economy, Isa Pantami, in a statement on Monday.</p>
<p>
<span class="ds-1col file file-image file-image-jpeg view-mode-embedded  centered clearfix block-story-object block-story-object-resource block-story-object-resource-image"><br />
<span class="block-story-object-asset"><img class="media-element file-embedded" typeof="foaf:Image" src="https://saharareporters.com/sites/default/files/styles/normal_medium/public/images%20-%202022-04-04T113121.107_1.jpeg?itok=UKg-DHwe" alt="" /></span><span class="block-story-object-content"></span><br />
</span>
</p>
<p>According to him, the move is part of the implementation of the NIN-SIM linkage Policy of the government.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>The statement was jointly signed by the Director, Public Affairs, Nigerian Communications Commission, Ikechukwu Adinde; and Head, Corporate Communications, National Identity Management Commission, Kayode Adegoke.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Pantami commended Nigerians and legal residents for their support during the exercise to link the NIN to SIM.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>It added that over 125 million SIMs have so far had their NINs submitted for immediate linkage, verification and authentication. Similarly, NIMC has issued over 78 million unique NINs to date.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>The statement partly reads, “President Buhari graciously approved the many requests to extend deadlines for the NIN-SIM linkage. At this point, however, Government has determined that the NIN-SIM Policy implementation can proceed, as machinery has already been put in place to ensure compliance by citizens and legal residents. The implementation impacts on the government’s strategic planning, particularly in the areas of security and socio-economic projections.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>“President Buhari has approved the implementation of the policy with effect from the 4th of April, 2022. Consequently, the Federal Government has directed all Telcos to strictly enforce the Policy on all SIMs issued (existing and new) in Nigeria. Outgoing calls will subsequently be barred for telephone lines that have not complied with the NIN-SIM linkage Policy from the 4th of April, 2022.”</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Some days ago, the Nigerian government again announced the extension of the deadline for the ongoing national identification number (NIN) and subscriber identity module (SIM) integration exercise by a few days. The exercise was meant to end on Thursday, March 31, 2022.</p>
</div>
<p><a href="https://saharareporters.com/2022/04/04/nigerian-government-directs-mtn-other-telecom-companies-bar-calls-sim-cards-not-linked">Source link </a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http:///www.latestnewstoday.com.ng/nigerian-government-directs-mtn-other-telecom-companies-to-bar-calls-from-sim-cards-not-linked-with-national-identity-number-nin/">Nigerian Government Directs MTN, Other Telecom Companies To Bar Calls From SIM Cards Not Linked With National Identity Number, NIN</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http:///www.latestnewstoday.com.ng">Latest News Today</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>http:///www.latestnewstoday.com.ng/nigerian-government-directs-mtn-other-telecom-companies-to-bar-calls-from-sim-cards-not-linked-with-national-identity-number-nin/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
